原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     Sakura的小书包  glida  海云生
翻译     屯栗子  tong大梨  余欢  布塔
校对     布塔
时间轴   西·查  caroline  今  壬虚浪影
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔
尽管这样的一个夜晚似乎是
So even though when it appears as if an evening like this
为了表彰我们的学术成就的
is meant to honor us for our academic achievements,
将军队集会
然而我想请求各位同学
I instead ask my fellow classmates
向引领我们的将军致敬
to honor the generals that lead us.
如果没有父母和老师
Without our parents and our teachers,
我们就会是对未来的战斗毫无准备的士兵
we would be troops unprepared for the battles that lay ahead of us.
我们知道未来的路并不好走
We know the road won't be easy.
但有了你们的爱和信任
But with your love and your faith,
我们肯定能顺利地走下去
we can be certain we'll find a way.
所以我希望接下来的请求不会太过分
So I hope it's not going too far out of line
请同学们起立
to ask my classmates to rise...
利用这个机会表示感谢
and to take this opportunity to thank you...
感谢老师
our teachers...
感谢父母
and our parents...
感谢他们帮我们成为理想中的自己
for helping us become who we're meant to be.
希望你们喜欢这掌声  因为等到明天
I hope you enjoyed that because tomorrow
我们又要让你们抓狂了
we'll be back to driving you crazy.
太棒了
It was incredible.
我想问个问题  怎么才能克隆这个家伙
Here's my question: How do we clone this guy?
怎么才能克隆他
How do we clone him?
干得漂亮
Great job.
-谢谢  -打扰一下
- Thank you. - Excuse me.
-请问是埃德加夫妇吗  -威尔逊老师
- Mr. And Mr. Edgar? - Ms. Wilson!
这位是威尔逊老师
Guys, this is Ms. Wilson,
我的历史与政府老师
my history and government teacher.
幸会
A pleasure.
早有耳闻
We've heard so much about you.
-是吗  -你的课堂
- Have you? - Well, your class.
卢斯总是提起
Luce can't stop talking about it.
是吗
Is that so?
威尔逊老师很严厉  但还是我最喜欢的老师之一
Ms. Wilson's tough, but still one of my favorites.
你喜欢我的演讲吗
Did you like my speech?
喜欢
I did.
威尔逊老师总是说
Ms. Wilson's always saying
我们应该直抒胸臆  不计代价
we should speak our minds no matter the cost.
我同意
Amen to that.
很高兴终于见到你了
Well, it's great to finally meet you.
我也是
You too.
卢斯是我们最好的学生之一
Luce is, uh, one of our best.
他是学校里重要的榜样人物
He's an important example to the school.
我们很为他骄傲
We're very proud of him.
应该的
You should be.
失陪一下  丹
Excuse me. Dan...
我不想再演讲一次了
I don't want to give another one.
为什么  他们请你合情合理
Why? It makes sense they asked you.
你讲得很好
You did a great job.
我只不过是发表了一次演讲
I literally just gave a speech.
你做的公共演讲越多
The more public speaking you do,
申请好大学就越容易
the better it'll look for college.
你答应他们了吧
You told them you'd do it, right?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
威尔逊老师似乎人挺好的
So Ms. Wilson seems nice.
很严厉
Stern...
-你想说她是个婊子吗  -彼得
- Don't you mean a bitch? - Peter!
人们嘴上说严厉  意思就是婊  你也一样
When people say stern, they mean bitch. You meant bitch.
-你只是不想直接说出来  -不  我说的是严厉
- You didn't want to say bitch - No, I said stern.
因为你不想政治不正确
because you didn't want to be politically incorrect
-但你就是想说她是婊子  -不
- but you meant bitch. - No.
我知道严厉是什么意思  谢谢
I know what stern means, thank you.
但她确实是个婊子
She is a bitch though.
我们能不能别诋毁一个
Can we not denigrate a woman
可能为了当一个领导者
who probably had to assume certain characteristics
而不得不表现出某种特征的女人
in order to attain a leadership role?
不过  你不是说最喜欢她的课吗
Anyway, I thought you said it was your favorite class.
-我喜欢那个学科  -他喜欢那个学科
- I like the subject. - He liked the subject.
尽管老师很婊
In spite of the bitch thing.
好吧  你可以批评有权势的女性
Okay, it's fine to criticize powerful women.
但别用带有性别歧视的语言
Just don't use the sexist language.
我们俩都知道了
Strung together copy.
很好
Nice!
你应该谈谈自己
You should make it personal.
什么
What?
他们让你下次做的演讲
The next speech they want you to give,
谈谈自己
make it about you.
好
Okay.
听着
And listen...
你是个很棒的演讲者
You're a really good public speaker
还是个出色的辩论者
and you're an excellent debater.
但你有自己的故事可以讲述
But you have your own story to tell
我觉得你应该讲自己的故事
and I think you should tell it.
会激发人们的共鸣
It gives people something to grab onto.
我管得太多了吗
Am I overstepping?
你的建议很好
It's good advice.
我只是想帮你
Just want to be helpful.
你帮到了
You are.
我要继续忙了
I'm going to get back to work now.
好
Okay.
抱歉打扰了你
Sorry for interrupting.
差点就把你的手夹断了
You're gonna lose a limb like that.
看到我的三角函数课本了吗  我昨天放在这的
See my trig textbook? I stashed it here yesterday.
没看到  欧力基
No, it's not here, Orlicki.
-我靠  -你知道
- Fuck me. - You do realize
每个人都有自己的储物柜吧
everyone gets their own locker, right?
知道  但我的在楼的另一边
Yeah. But mine's on the other side of the building,
-每次都害我迟到  -欧力基
- makes me late all the time. - Shit! Orlicki!
听说昨晚有人叫这个家伙再演讲一次
Heard our boy here got asked to give another speech last night?
-真的吗  -他简直是
- Seriously? - Motherfucking
纳尔逊·曼德拉再世
Nelson Mandela over here!
不知道为什么从来没人让我去演讲
I don't get why I never get asked.
因为你成绩差
'cause you're a C+ student.
整篇演讲都会是关于黄片和大麻的
The entire speech would be about porn and blunts.
有道理
Fair enough.
靠  看呀
Shit! Check it out!
女士们
Hey, yo, ladies!
-斯蒂芬妮·金  你好吗  -我们走
- Stephanie Kim, what's good? - Let's go.
你为什么盯着卢斯看  斯蒂芬妮
Why you staring at Luce, Stephanie?
我在和你说话呢
I'm talking to you.
不是每个人都喜欢你的大嘴的
Not everyone likes your big mouth.
你妈喜欢
Your mama does.
她爱我的大嘴
She loves my big mouth.
喜欢我舔她的逼
Loves it all over that pussy!
你太恶心了
Man, you're so gross!
抱歉
Sorry, bro.
训练时见
Hey yo, I'll see you all at practice.
法律就是法律
A law is a law.
这曾经也是法律
Pole-tests used to be law.
种族隔离和划红线也是
So was segregation. Red lining.
这不一样
That's not the same.
你的理由呢
Explain why.
就是不一样
It's just not.
以前的情况和现在不一样
Things were different back then.
怎么不一样
Different how?
比如时代不一样
Well, like that was a different time.
社会规范不一样
Social norms were different.
人们的期望和态度也不一样
People's expectations, their attitudes...
这对你来说不重要吗
Is this not important to you?
回答我
Well?
重要
It is.
你得说得更清楚一点
You might want to speak more clearly.
我听不清你说什么
I can't hear you.
重要
It is.
记住了  对她而言
Keep in mind, that for her,
这个知识可能无关紧要  但你而言
this knowledge is incidental but for you
可能事关生死
it can be life or death.
所以你需要足够严肃地
So you might want to treat this material
对待这个主题  米克斯先生
with the seriousness it deserves, Mr. Meeks.
这也让我想起  我差不多
Which reminds me, I'm almost done
把你们的作业改完了  我道歉
grading your assignments. I apologize,
比平常花的时间久了一点  但是
it's taking me a little longer than usual but,
你们很快就会收到反馈
you'll have them back soon.
好了
All right...
德肖恩
Deshaun...
Deshaun!
我们来看看里面
Let's have a look in here. Okay...
-看看  -感觉怪怪的
- Let's see... - That feels funny!
是吗
Oh yeah?
这样呢
What about that?
怪吗
Does that feel funny?
周末去康奈尔玩怎么样
How do you feel about a weekend trip to Cornell?
-这周末吗  -对
- This weekend? - Yeah.
玛吉的姐姐说她会打点关系
Maggie's sister said she'd make a call
让卢斯能有和教授独处的时间
and get Luce some one-on-one time with the professor.
这周末我们要参加新生儿派对
This weekend we have the sip-and-see.
-天呐  -你不想去的话
- Oh my God! - If you don't want to go,
应该早点说  对吧
you should have said, right?
嗯  我不是不想去
Yeah, well, it's not that I don't want to go. I mean,
-相信我  我不想去  但是  -你就是讨厌婴儿
- Trust me. I don't want to go, but... - No, you just hate babies.
我不讨厌婴儿
I do not hate babies.
我超喜欢婴儿
I mean, I love babies!
但你讨厌婴儿
But you hate babies.
我只是惊讶于你把
Well, I'm just shocked you're prioritizing
前任的新生儿派对看得比儿子的大学教育更重
your ex's sip-and-see over your son's college education,
不过这只是我的个人想法
but hey, that's just me.
好吧  我懂你意思了
Okay. Punchline and point made.
好吧  你来决定带什么东西
Okay, fine. You're in charge of picking up
去参加新生儿派对
whatever someone brings to a sip-and-see.
好的  回家见
Got it. Okay, see you at home.
回见
See ya.
喂
Hello?
没错  是我
Yes, this is Amy.
各就各位
On your mark...
预备
Set...
跑
Go!
新星高中
将军运动场
-埃德加夫人  -你好
- Mrs. Edgar. - Hi.
感谢你抽出时间来一趟
I appreciate you coming back down here.
必须要为重要的事情腾出时间
Well, you have to make time for what's important.
说得没错
Ain't that the truth.
-学生们有你这样的老师真幸运  -谢谢
- Kids are lucky to have you. - Thank you.
-卢斯也一样  -我们有他真幸运
- Luce too. - We're lucky to have him.
我们很关心他的成功
We care a great deal about his success.
-我和彼得也是  -当然
- Peter and I too. - Of course.
而且我知道家庭环境很重要
And I know context matters.
请坐
Please, sit.
考虑到卢斯的背景
Given Luce's background,
你和彼得一定遇到了很多难题
you and Peter must have faced quite a few challenges.
语言障碍  文化冲击
the language barrier, the culture shock.
他的适应能力很强
He's a resilient kid.
是的  但这也证明了你们的培养有方
He is. But it's also a testament to your parenting.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
我们得到了很多支持  尤其是最开始的时候
We had a lot of support, especially in the early days. I mean,
把一个孩子从战区接出来
you don't pull a kid out of a war zone
让他变成卢斯这样  没有许多帮助是不行的
and have him turn out like Luce without a lot of help.
我想也是
I bet.
所以我很难开口
Which is why this is so difficult.
难开口
Difficult?
上周  我给班上布置了一份作业
Last week, the class was given an assignment
以一个历史人物的口吻写篇论文
to write in the voice of an historical figure.
有学生选择了大萧条开始时的罗斯福总统
Some students picked FDR at the start of the Great Depression
甚至是猪湾的菲德尔·卡斯特罗
or even Fidel Castro at the Bay of Pigs.
目的是让他们开动脑筋
The goal was to get them to think outside of the box.
只是想确保你明白我为什么谈这个
Just want to make sure you understand where I'm coming from.
请看
Please.
这个弗兰茨·法农是谁
Who is this Frantz Fanon?
一个泛非洲革命者
He was a pan-African revolutionary.
他主张暴力是必要的净化力量
He argued that violence was a necessary cleansing force,
使殖民地人民摆脱殖民者需要它
that it was needed to free colonized people from their rulers.
-你教这个吗  -不教
- You-you teach this? - I don't.
听着
Look,
我不会假装明白
I won't pretend to know
卢斯要如何面对自身的某些方面
what it's like for Luce to confront certain aspects of who he is
我也无权
and it's not within my purview
说一个十岁前一直在...
to say what a boy who spent his first 10 years in...
厄立特里亚
Eritrea.
没错
Right.
那会是什么样子
What that might have been like,
他为了融入这里又做出了哪些调整
what kind of adjustments he must have made in order to fit in here.
我不知道他的治疗详情
And I don't know the details of his treatment...
你肯定听说过他经历了数年的恢复
Well, I'm sure you've heard he went through years of recovery
他没有表现出...
and he showed no signs of...
-我无意暗示  -我只想说清楚
- I-I didn't mean to imply... - No, I just want to be clear that
不管他那时遭受或造成了什么暴力
whatever violence he both suffered and inflicted during that time
都处理过了  已经治疗了
was dealt with, it's been processed.
当然
Of course.
但是鉴于现在校园安全的情况
But with the climate around school security the way it is right now,
你应该能理解我的担心
you can understand my concern.
是的
Yes.
所以我觉得我需要搜查他的储物柜
Which is why I felt I needed to search his locker.
-你说什么  -艾米
- I'm sorry? - Amy...
他就是写了篇论文
He wrote a paper.
可是在这篇论文中他描述
A paper in which he describes
他认为政治问题的解决方法
his belief that the solution to a political problem
就是枪杀那些你不认同的人
is to gun down those with whom you disagree.
好吧  但他是站在这个人物的立场上
Right. But he was assuming a character.
这是作业要求的  你...
The assignment called for this and you...
我在他的储物柜发现了这个
I found this in his locker.
-不  -艾米
- No. - Amy.
不  抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
我尊重我儿子的隐私
I respect my son's privacy.
他写了一篇论文吓到了你  行
Now, he wrote a paper that scared you. Fine.
那是你和他之间的事
That's between you and him.
但我不会  我不会侵犯他应有的隐私权
But I won't, I will not violate his right to the privacy he's owed.
这是烟花
They're fireworks.
非法且非常危险的烟花
Illegal and very dangerous fireworks.
可以在墙上炸出个洞  更别说...
They could put a hole in the wall, let alone...
你到底想说什么
Where are you going with this?
现在只有我知道这件事
Right now I'm the only one who knows about them,
但如果别人发现呢
but what if someone else were to find them?
如果一个不像你我这样了解卢斯的人
If someone who didn't know Luce the way you and I do
意外发现这些烟花
were to stumble on this
再加上他这样背景的人写下这种言论...
within the context of his background having written this...
你拿着
Take them.
和他谈谈
Talk to him.
他这个模范对我们学校太重要  不能让他搞砸
Who he is is too important to this school for him to fuck it up.
他不能搞砸
He can't fuck it up.
请和他谈谈
Talk to him, please.
我会的
I will.
是你一直在谈论斯蒂芬妮
You're the one who keeps talking about Stephanie.
-我没有  -你到底什么毛病
- No, I'm not! - The fuck is wrong with you?
闭嘴  放开我
Shut it! Get off me!
你就该闭上你的嘴  混蛋
You should have kept your mouth shut, little shit.
我告诉过你
I told you!
你们搞什么  别这样
What the hell! Come on!
-他告诉了所有人  -去你的
- He told everybody! - Fuck you!
科里  科里  科里
Corey, Corey, Corey, Corey, Corey!
如果这事传开  就怪你们两个
If this gets out, it's on your two.
你们两个
Both of you!
-有什么事吗  -没事  教练
- Everything okay? - Everything's fine, coach.
卢斯  来我办公室
Luce, my office.
好的
Sure thing.
你从头到尾读完了
You read the whole thing?
是的
Yeah.
孩子确实会被一些思想迷住
Okay, yeah, kids get taken with ideas.
他可能在网上偶然看到弗兰茨·法农
Look, he probably stumbled across Frantz Fanon on the internet
过分着迷了
and went overboard.
我大学时读了共产党宣言
I read the Communist Manifesto when I was an undergrad
那一个月见人都叫同志
and called people comrade for a month.
好吧  我觉得他很聪明  不会那样
Yeah, well, I think he's a little too smart for that.
储物柜里放爆炸物不叫聪明
Not too smart to have explosives in his locker.
-那是烟花  -非法烟花
- They're fireworks. - Illegal fireworks
-我上网查了  -那也还是
- that have explosive capacity, - Still...
具有猎枪冲击那种爆炸力
I Googled this, of a shotgun blast.
那是烟花
They're fireworks.
没什么好震惊的
It's not shocking.
确实令人震惊
That is shocking.
好吧  那怎么办
Okay, so what?
-什么怎么办  -什么  什么  我们的
- So what? - What? What, our...
即将在毕业礼上致辞的优秀青年儿子
teenage soon-to-be valedictorian son is,
-暗地里是个激进分子吗  -不
- is secretly a radical? - No.
-恐怖分子吗  -不
- A terrorist? - No.
-当然不是  -那是什么
- Of course not. - What then?
我不知道  只是确实有情况
I don't know. It's just something's going on
我想要及时处理
and I want to be in front of it.
糟糕
Shit.
艾米  你搞什么
Amy, what the fuck?
学校怎么样
How was school?
什么情况
What's going on?
没什么
Nothing.
学校怎么样  训练怎么样
How was school? How was practice?
跟平时一样
Uneventful.
傻
Psy.
-你吃饭了吗  -还没
- Have you eaten? - Not yet.
那好  你爸买了咖喱饭
Good, because your dad picked up curry.
棒
Sweet!
你把东西放好我们就开饭了
Okay, put your stuff down so we can eat.
-好的  -好
- Cool. - Great.
-等我来了再开吃  -好的
- Don't start without me. - We won't.
-刚刚什么情况  -我不想他知道
- What was that? - I don't want him to know
-我们翻了他的东西  -我们没翻
- we've gone through his things. - We didn't go through his things.
或是搞得像我们背着他找了老师
Or make it seem like we went behind his back to his teachers.
-艾米  -拜托  彼得
- Amy... - Come on, Pete.
我们花了多少年才让他变成现在这样
How many years did it take us to get him here?
多少个夜晚我爬到他床下
How many nights did I crawl underneath that bed
因为他太害怕不敢睡床上
because he was too scared to sleep in it?
我们建立的那份信任
What we've built. That trust.
我不会拿它冒险  不会
I won't risk it. I won't.
我把一切都准备好了
I got everything ready.
是的  我明天会去和医生谈
Yes, I'll be by to talk with the doctors tomorrow
然后就没问题了
and we'll be all set.
罗斯
Rose...
罗斯  我已经告诉你了
Rose, I told you already, okay?
好的  回头见
Okay. I'll see you soon.
我也爱你
I love you too.
好吧  谁告诉你们了
Okay, so who told you?
-告诉我们什么  -你们显然知道
- Told us what? - You clearly know.
我们知道什么
What do we know?
你们...你们不知道吗
You don't... you don't know?
你认为我们知道或不知道什么  亲爱的
What is it that you think we do or do not know, honey?
里夫斯教练让我当队长
Coach Reeves offered me Captain.
天啊  太棒了
Oh my God! That's amazing!
是的  酷毙了
Yeah! It's... it's dope.
他说我会是一些队友的好榜样
Says I'll be good example for certain teammates.
但要练田径以及准备辩论
But between track and debate prep,
还有威尔逊让我们做的额外作业
plus the extra shit Wilson has us doing...
什么意思
What, how do you mean?
没什么  只是...
Nothing. It's just...
你真的不喜欢她  是吧
You really don't like her, do you?
很复杂
It's complicated.
说来听听
Try me.
好吧  你们还记得斯蒂芬妮·金吧
Okay. You remember Stephanie Kim, right?
-有点...  -完全不记得
- Sort of... - Not a clue.
她之前来过一次
She came over one time last...
-继续说  -总之
- Go on. - Anyway.
几周前一次派对后
There were these rumors going around about her
开始有她的谣言
after this party a few weeks ago.
-什么谣言  -大家都在喝酒
- What kind of rumors? - People were drinking
没人知道到底发生了什么  但...
and no one really knows what happened, but...
斯蒂芬妮有点喝高了
Stephanie got kind of messed up.
和几个男生发生了一些事
Something happened with some guys.
然后威尔逊插手了
Then Wilson got involved
没人能真的证明什么
and no one really could prove anything
但她一直拿斯蒂芬妮举例
but she kept using Stephanie as like an example.
把她变成受害者
Turning her into a victim.
-具体呢  -这个
- How? - Well,
我们会讨论中东女性之类的话题
we'll be talking about women in Middle East or something
她专门针对斯蒂芬妮  说一些什么
and she singles her out, says some shit like,
"我们都切身了解女性鼓起勇气"
"We all know firsthand how important it is for women
"站出来反抗有多重要"
to have the courage to stand up, to fight."
我不明白
I don't understand.
这也不算是针对她吧
It's not exactly singling her out.
是她表述的方式
It's how she says it.
好像每个人在她看来都是个象征
Like everyone's a symbol to her.
斯蒂芬妮  德肖恩  我们的存在
Stephanie, Deshaun, we all exist
都是为了证实她眼中的世界
to confirm the world is the way she sees it.
她也这么对你吗
So does she do that kind of thing with you?
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我就是个招牌男孩
I'm a fucking poster boy.
克服了悲惨过去的黑人男孩
Black kid who overcame his tragic past,
美国为什么能成功的例子  都是狗屁
the example why America works. It's bullshit.
所以你不喜欢她给你加标签
So you don't like her labeling you?
我不喜欢象征主义
I don't like tokenism.
惩罚一个符合刻板印象的人
What's the difference between punishing someone
和奖励一个不符合刻板印象的人  有什么区别吗
for being a stereotype and rewarding them if they're not?
其中一个有好处
One of the two comes with benefits.
你所说的好处
What you'd call a benefit,
在我看来是不请自来的责任
I'd call a responsibility I didn't ask for.
好吧  那说实话的责任呢
Okay, what about responsibility to tell the truth?
-什么  -彼得
- What? - Peter...
你得到的其中一个好处就是无罪推定
So, one of the benefits you get is benefit of the doubt.
-为自己解释的机会  -为自己解释
- A chance to explain yourself. - Explain myself?
-够了  -其他学生可没有这待遇
- Enough. - Whereas another student might not. So...
你还有没有要跟我们交代的
You have anything you want to tell us?
-彼得  别这样  -交代什么
- Peter, stop. - About what?
问你妈吧
Ask your mom.
把饭吃了
Finish your food.
新星将军队
哈丽特·威尔逊
新星高中
新星高中世界史教师
曾就读于阿拉巴马州立大学
居住于维吉尼亚州  阿灵顿市
有一名家庭成员
家人和亲属
罗斯玛丽·威尔逊
妹妹
康复中心
在吗
Knock knock.
让我们过去
We've been summoned.
宝贝
Honey...
卢斯
我们得谈谈
早上有辩论练习  晚上见
埃德加检察官
Prosecutor Edgar,
今天要手下留情啊  你们都还好吗
take it easy on me today. How are you all doing?
很高兴你能来参加  威尔逊老师
Ms. Wilson, so glad you could join us.
卢斯希望有人能帮他演练一下
Luce was hoping to get some help building his next case.
你和丹校长就是全明星阵容了
I figure you and Principal Dan are the all stars.
我们今年能打进决赛  对不对
We're going to nationals again this year, right?
-绝对的  -好样的
- 100 percent. - Boom!
所以说他是我的得意弟子
That's why this one's my thoroughbred.
好  这就开始吧
Okay, let's have it.
威尔逊老师
Ms. Wilson...
好啊  让我们听听你准备了什么
Of course. Let's, uh, let's hear what you got.
-你在做什么  -天呐  彼得
- What are you doing? - Jesus, Pete!
直接把它们扔了不就好了吗
Doesn't it make sense just to get rid of them?
它们太危险了
They're so dangerous.
我们得留着直到搞清楚整件事为止
We hang on to them until we get to the bottom of this.
放在这里就没事了
They'll be safe here.
怎么了
What?
我的论点基于两个案例
My argument is premised on two court cases:
1975年的格斯诉洛佩兹案
Goss v. Lopez, 1975,
以及1985年的新泽西州诉TLO案
and New Jersey v. T.L.O., 1985.
在格斯案中  俄亥俄州一家学校以不良行为为由
In Goss, an Ohio school suspended nine students
责令九名学生停课查看
for delinquent behavior,
但最高法院认为
but the Supreme Court found
不经正当程序剥夺学生受教育权
that depriving students of their right to an education
是对学生公民权利的侵害
without due process is a violation of their civil rights.
威尔逊老师  你同意这一观点吗
Ms. Wilson, do you agree with that?
什么
I'm sorry?
你认同这些学生的
Do you agree that those kids
公民权利受侵犯了吗
were deprived of their civil rights?
我不了解案件细节  但是
I don't know the specifics of the case, but...
-原则上...  -原则上没问题  对吧
- the principal... - Principal makes sense, right?
教育权属于公民权利
Education is a civil right.
人人都享有公民权利
Everyone should have civil rights.
-对  -在第二个案件中
- Right. - In the second case
一名学生被指控在学校洗手间抽烟
a student is accused of smoking in the school bathroom,
但没有证据
but there's no proof.
这一论断完全是基于一名教师的怀疑
The charge is premised on a teacher's suspicion.
所以学校搜了她的钱包  发现了香烟
So the principal searched her purse and found cigarettes
以及大麻相关用品
and marijuana-related paraphernalia.
你认同这一做法吗
Do you agree with that?
法院怎么宣判的
What did the court say?
法院认为学生在学校
The court found that students
合理隐私期待
界定自然人在什么场合拥有隐私的要素之一
只有自然人能证明拥有合理隐私期待的前提下
才能享受美国第四宪法修正案的保护
享有较弱的隐私期待
have a reduced expectation of privacy in schools.
有道理
It makes sense.
是吗
Does it?
学校是一个特殊的社会机构
A school is a unique social institution.
其中的成员是法律上的未成年人
It's populated by people who aren't adults in the eyes of the law.
必须上学的人
People who have to be here.
-学生  -对
- Students. - Yes.
学生不算完全的人
Students are half people.
卢斯
Luce,
你有什么威尔逊老师能回答的
is there a specific question you have
具体问题要问吗
that Ms. Wilson might be able to address?
有的
Totally.
谢谢  坦尼森老师
Thanks Ms. Tennyson.
我希望威尔逊老师能帮助我解答的问题
Basically my question that I hope Ms. Wilson can help me with
与这个弱隐私期待
is around this idea of reduced expectation
以及法院对学生公民权的认可有关
versus the affirmation by the court of student civil rights.
比如说如何判定
Like what are the criteria for evaluating
侵害隐私的行为
what's a violation of privacy?
隐私权属于公民权吗
Is privacy a civil right?
是的
I think so.
也许法律没那么明确
Maybe the law isn't so sure.
如果我不经你同意搜查你的办公桌
If I went through your desk without you knowing,
你会感觉这侵犯了你的隐私吗
would you feel like your privacy was violated?
会
Yes, I would.
那么
So?
但是感觉不能成为法律依据
Feelings aren't a legal argument.
在新泽西州案中  那位老师
In the New Jersey case, the teacher assumed
以她的感觉判定那女孩犯了错
the girl was guilty because of her feelings.
那是合理的怀疑
That's called reasonable suspicion.
不准确  美国宪法规定
为了保护人们的合理隐私期待
此类搜查需要许可令
警察只需要这个就能搜查你的车
It's all the police need to search your car.
所以关键在于合理的定义
So it's about what's reasonable.
这是法院的事
That's what courts are for.
但其实只是在于人  对吗
Really it's just about people though, right?
在于对方的表现是否符合我们对其的认知
Whether they conform to what we think they are.
不是那么简单的
It's not that simple.
世上没有简单的事
Nothing ever is.
非常感谢你的帮助  威尔逊老师
Thank you so much for your help, Ms. Wilson.
很顺利  是不是
This was, this was great, right?
随时恭候
Any time.
天呐  这孩子真出色  是不是
God, that kid is something else, isn't he?
好了  大家放下手机
All right, people, phones away.
我看见你了  萨莎
I see you, Sasha.
还有你  斯蒂芬妮·金
And you too, Stephanie Kim.
-好  -表演时间到
- All right. - It's show time!
你搞砸了  另外兄弟
You fucked up. And bro,
你不能把欧力基压在柜门上打
you can't just go slamming Orlicki against a locker.
他跟其他人胡说八道
He's out there telling everybody.
又不是说大家都不知道
It's nothing half the school didn't already know.
另外  我和斯蒂芬妮谈了
Besides, I talked to Stephanie.
你们俩还说话
You two still talk?
不算吧  但总有人得去解决这件事
Not really, but someone had to resolve this
-免得出事  -她没问题吧
- before it blows up. - Is she gonna be cool?
-对  -她不会惹事吧
- Yeah. - Is she gonna be cool?
不会有事的  兄弟
Everything's going to be cool, man.
和欧力基和好  行吗
Just squash the beef with Orlicki, all right?
-科里  -行  兄弟  随便吧
- Corey! - All right, man. Whatever.
德肖恩胆子真大
Deshaun's one bold-ass nigga.
自从威尔逊把他赶出校队
Since Wilson got him tossed off the team,
他就自暴自弃了
he's been messed up.
回头见  兄弟
I'll catch you later, man.
-嘿  -好
- Yo. - Yeah.
我们说好了的
We agreed on this.
你和我一起住的话  你得负责任
If you live with me, you have to be responsible for...
我只要你乖乖服药
All I ask is if you're staying on top of your medication.
我知道医生说了什么  罗斯玛丽
I know what the doctor said, Rosemary.
这不等于我没意见
It doesn't mean I'm comfortable with it.
全家人里面
Out of everyone in this family,
只有我一次又一次帮你
you know that I've been there for you time and time again.
我讨厌那样
I resent that.
我得挂了  罗斯  我们今晚再聊
I gotta go, Rose. We'll talk tonight.
-一切都还好吗  -都很好
- Everything okay? - Everything's fine.
家务事吗
Family stuff?
对  私事
Personal business, yes.
懂了
Gotcha.
谢谢你今早的指导
Thanks for your guidance this morning.
对我理清论点真的很有帮助
It really helped make my case.
我很高兴
I'm glad.
你是想见我吗
You wanted to see me?
我想跟你谈谈你的作业  卢斯
I wanted to talk to you about your assignment, Luce.
作业怎么了
What about it?
我假定你和你妈谈过了
I assumed you spoke to your mother...
我都还没有回家  怎么可能和我妈谈过
I haven't gotten it back yet. How could I talk to my mom about it?
我直说吧
Well, I'll just say, uh...
读完你的作业  我对你陈述的
After reading through it, I have some concerns
一些观点有些担忧
about some of the arguments you made.
那不是我的观点
Well they aren't mine.
什么
Excuse me?
那些论点  是弗兰茨·法农的
The arguments, they're Frantz Fanon's.
我知道
I realize that.
作业要求以他的口吻写
The assignment was to write in his voice.
你真认为我相信那一套
You really think I believe that stuff?
我不知道
Well, I don't know.
如果我不认识你  我读完那作业
If I didn't know you, Luce, it would be reasonable for me
完全有理由认为你...
to read that assignment and conclude...
但你认识我
But you do know me.
听我说
Look, um,
吓到你我很抱歉
I'm sorry if I scared you.
我只想把作业做好
I just wanted to do a good job.
你的确完成得不错
You did do a good job.
我懂
I mean, I get it.
-懂什么  -我懂
- Get what? - Well, I get
如果一个在学开车前就先会开枪的人
how someone who learned how to shoot a gun before driving a car
写那么一篇东西
writing something like that
可能会吓到别人
might make someone freaked out.
我只是希望你知道我不是那样的人  威尔逊老师
I just hope you know me better than that, Ms. Wilson.
我也觉得你不是  卢斯
I like to think that I do, Luce.
你还有什么想跟我谈的吗
Is there anything else you wanted to talk to me about?
没有了
No.
告诉你妈  我希望她给我打个电话
But tell your mom I'd like her to call me.
为什么
Why?
因为我想和她聊聊
Because I want to speak with her.
聊什么
What about? I mean,
除非你们有私交  否则我猜和我有关
I guess it's about me unless you guys are friends or something.
请让她给我打电话  卢斯
Please have her call me, Luce.
谢谢你过来
Thank you for stopping in.
好的
Of course.
威尔逊老师
Hey, Ms. Wilson...
你最喜欢哪个节日
What's your favorite holiday?
-什么  -你最喜欢哪个节日
- Excuse me? - What's your favorite holiday?
我不确定  大概圣诞节吧
I don't know. Christmas maybe.
我最喜欢独立日
Mine is Independence Day.
我来美国之前
Before I came here,
我一个节日也没听说过
I didn't know a single holiday and
我记得我妈努力跟我解释各种节日
I remember my mom trying to explain what they were.
没有听说过节日的话  很难理解
It's a hard concept to grasp if you've never heard of it,
但是
but,
搞懂所有节日后  我最喜欢的节日
once I learned them all, my favorite, hands down,
毫无疑问  一直都是独立日
has always been Independence Day.
为什么
Why is that?
我喜欢它的含义
I like what it represents.
自由
Freedom,
力量
strength,
个性
individuality.
另外我也喜欢烟花  那种光芒
Also I love the fireworks. The lights.
卢斯  我要提醒你  你在这里是个学生
Luce, I'd like to remind you that you're still a student here
我是你的老师
and I am your teacher.
无论你把什么视为不公
And regardless of what you may view as some sort of injustice
-你在说什么  -或者不合理
- What are you talking about? - or unfair,
记住这里的规矩
just remember how things are organized around here.
当然了  回头见
Totally. I'll see you around.
-丘萨克的财报  -谢谢  贝丝
- The financials from Cusack. - Thanks, Beth.
季终支出结算  是不是
Quarter end payments went out, right?
对
Yes.
怎么
Yeah?
威尔逊老师  你好吗
Ms. Wilson. How are you?
她为什么给你打电话
Why is she calling you?
我记得我也还是家长之一呢
Well, last I checked I'm one of two parents.
没错  但她之前都是跟我沟通的
Yeah, but she was communicating with me
现在怎么变成给你打电话了
and now she's calling you?
好吧  她可以跟任一家长谈论我们儿子的问题
Well, we're both available to talk about our son.
这个女人对卢斯抱有恨意
This woman has some kind of vendetta against Luce.
-恨意  真的吗  -是的
- Vendetta? Really? - Yeah.
她之前跟他有过节  而现在
She has some thing with him and now,
现在她试图对我们分而治之
now she's trying to divide and conquer.
说话真有水平
Nice word choice.
她之前那样对斯蒂芬妮·金
What she did with Stephanie Kim
现在又想这样对卢斯
and what she's trying to do now with Luce,
她对不同的孩子用不同标准
this woman holds different kids to different standards based on...
你有见到或听到她对那女孩做的事情吗
Did you see or hear what she did to that girl?
-我听到的足够下判断了  -从卢斯那里听的
- I've heard enough to know. - From Luce, yeah.
是的  从我们儿子那里听的  他对我们一直很诚实
Yes, from our son, who has always been honest with us.
除了在储物柜里藏着非法烟花
Except about having illegal fireworks in his locker.
那件事他并没有说谎
He didn't lie about that.
-是吗  -没告诉我们
- Is that so? - Not telling us
和说谎可是两码事
and lying are two different things.
如果他做坏事是有模式的呢
And what if there's a pattern here?
-模式  -没错
- A pattern? - Yeah.
论文  烟花  威胁老师
The paper, the fireworks, the threat...
彼得
Peter...
-我们至少得坦诚面对  -绝对不行
- We have to be at least open to the possibility - Absolutely not.
儿子可能做某些事的可能
that our son is capable of...
做什么  做什么的可能
Of what? Capable of what?
告诉我你知道他是个好孩子  彼得
Tell me you know he's a good kid, Pete.
告诉我如果真的出事
Tell me if shit hits the fan,
我们不会舍弃我们的儿子
we aren't about to abandon our son.
-我们当然不会舍弃他  -我们的黑人儿子得面对
- Of course we're not going to abandon him. - Our black son to a system
一个本来就想整死他的体系
that already wants to shit all over him.
我们的职责是保护他  支持他
It's our job to protect him, to have his back.
那只一部分  我们还有一种职责
That's part of it. It's our job
-是做正确的事  -是为他
- to do what's right. - By him.
是为他做正确的事
To do what's right by him.
-卢斯  -怎么
- Luce! - Yeah?
-有时间吗  -你说过会按我的方法做的
- Got a minute? - You said you'd do this my way.
-是的  -怎么了
- Yeah. - What's up?
你有没有威胁你的老师
Did you threaten your teacher?
-亲爱的  -什么
- Honey... - Excuse me?
你听到我说的了
You heard me.
我有没有威胁...
Did I threaten...?
威尔逊老师打电话了
Ms. Wilson called.
威尔逊老师说我威胁她了吗
Ms. Wilson said I threatened her?
有没有
Did you?
-她说什么  -她说...
- What did she say? - She said...
别管她说了什么  你干什么了
Never mind what she said. What did you do?
她让我过去见她
She asked me to come and see her.
然后
And?
我感谢她帮我理清辩论的论点
I thanked her for helping me with my debate case.
-她帮了你  -是的  她跟丹校长
- She helped you? - Yeah, her and Principal Dan.
我为什么要威胁她
Why would I threaten her?
她想跟你谈什么事情
What did she want to talk to you about?
一篇论文  我们之前有误会
A paper. We had a misunderstanding.
我为此道歉
I apologized for it.
你有没有提到独立日
You say anything about the 4th of July?
-什么  -亲爱的
- What? - Honey...
-还有烟花  -那怎么能算是威胁
- About fireworks? - How is that a threat?
你到底有没有提到独立日
Did you or did you not say something about the 4th of July?
我说独立日是我最爱的节日
I said the 4th of July was my favorite holiday.
你为什么那样说
Why would you say that?
因为我以为我们在聊天
Because I thought we were having a conversation.
她说我威胁她了
She says I threatened her?
卢斯  我需要你跟我说实话
Luce, I need you to be straight with me for a second.
-我什么时候不说实话了  -喂
- When am I not? - Hey!
好的
Sure.
你有什么想跟我们交代的吗
So is there anything you want to tell us?
-没有  -确定吗
- No. - You sure about that?
确定什么  天啊  如果你们
Am I sure about what? Jesus, if you guys
-想问我...  -你为什么
- want to ask me... - Why did you have
把非法烟花放在储物柜里
illegal fireworks in your locker?
-什么  -你为什么
- What? - Why did you have
把非法烟花放在储物柜里
illegal fireworks in your locker?
-我没有  -卢斯  别对我说谎
- I didn't. - Luce, don't lie to me.
-我没有  -卢斯
- I'm not. - Luce!
你怎么知道我储物柜里有什么
How would you know what's in my locker?
-哈丽特告诉我们的  -哈丽特的话可真多
- Harriet told us. - Harriet has a lot to say.
别管她说什么了  你到底放没放
Never mind what she said. Did you or didn't you?
-就我所知没有  -你知道吗
- Not that I know of. - Oh, you know what?
-不管了  -我们的储物柜共用
- Fuck this. - We share lockers.
校队里的男生都共用储物柜
The guys on the team share lockers.
欧力基的储物柜里有我的东西  我的里有他的东西
Half my shit is in Orlicki's, half his shit is in mine.
大部分情况下我都不知道储物柜里有什么东西
I don't know what 90% of the crap at the bottom is,
-更别说知道是谁的了  -所以
- let alone who it belongs to. - So...
所以我储物柜里的东西不全是我的
So not everything in my locker belongs to me.
那就好
Okay, good.
这就没事了
That's good.
这回你就明白了
Now, you understand
不仅要搞清楚
why it's important to know
储物柜里有什么东西  还要知道是谁的
not only what's in your locker, but who it belongs to.
-是的  -对吧
- Yes. - Right?
你不能盲目地相信别人
You can't blindly trust people to...
你还真信这套鬼话
Okay. You seriously buy this shit?
不是吧
Seriously?
你是说恰好有人把非法烟花放在你储物柜里
So someone just happens to leave a bag of illegal fireworks
而且你还不知道是谁
in your locker and you have no idea?
然后有个你不喜欢的老师
And then this teacher, who you don't like,
无理地搜了你的储物柜  找到了这些烟花
unjustifiably searches your locker and finds them.
你只是巧合之中的
You're just an unlucky victim
-不幸受害者  是吗  -是真的
- of circumstance, right? - It's the truth.
我可不这么觉得
That doesn't sound like the truth to me.
我觉得你说的是狗屁
That sounds like bullshit.
你相信我吗
You believe me?
我们能解决这个问题
We can figure this out.
选手德
什么时候能见面
我没跟任何人说过斯蒂芬妮和派对的事
I didn't tell anyone about Stephanie or the party.
科里应该冷静下来
Corey should calm the fuck down.
我跟他说过了  一切正常
I talked to him, everything's fine.
是啊  你他妈跟我脖子上的淤青说一切正常吧
Yeah, tell that to the bruise on my fucking neck.
你得理解他的处境
You gotta understand where he's coming from.
你爸上了达特茅斯[名校]Your dad went to Dartmouth.
你爷爷上了达特茅斯
Your granddad went to Dartmouth.
连你的狗大概都能上达特茅斯
Your dog could probably get into Dartmouth.
科里可没有这种背景
Corey doesn't have that.
他只要惹上一点点事  就会成为下一个德肖恩
A whiff of something up with him and he's the next Deshaun.
可不能晚上乱逛抽大麻  兄弟
Can't be walking around at night smelling high, bro.
你真的觉得有人能阻止你吗
You seriously think someone's gonna stop you?
我也不想成为下一个德肖恩
I'm not interested in being the next Deshaun either.
你跟德肖恩不一样
You're not like Deshaun.
我们都是黑人  欧力基
We're both black, Orlicki.
确实  但他是那种黑人
Yeah, but he's like black-black.
那我是哪种黑人
Then what am I?
你是卢斯
You're Luce.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你去哪里了
Where were you?
我去跑步了  有什么事
I went for a run. What do you want?
我想向你道歉
I just wanted to apologize
为之前的事
for before.
-你父亲...  -觉得我是个骗子吗
- Your father... - ...thinks I'm a liar?
不是  他很困惑  我们都是
No, he-he's confused. We both are.
困惑什么事
Confused about what?
我跟你说过威尔逊的为人
I told you the kind of person Wilson is.
你不顺应她的心意
You don't conform to what she wants
那你就成了她的敌人
and suddenly you're the enemy.
听着
Look...
我明白别人对你期望过高可能显得不公平
I know it can seem unfair how much people expect of you.
但你不明白
You don't, though.
不可能明白
You can't.
有时候我那么努力
And sometimes I'm working so hard
想要维持这一切
to keep this all together,
-让我感觉一切都...  -都怎么
- it feels like it'll all just... - What?
-都怎么  -我不可能完美
- Just what? - I can't be perfect.
没有人期望你完美
No one expects you to be perfect.
威尔逊就是
Wilson does.
信不信由你  她只是在保护你
Believe it or not, she's just trying to protect you.
她是在保护我象征的意义
She's trying to protect her idea of me.
跟你和他一样
Same as you and him.
这么说不公平
That's not fair.
不公平不代表不是真的
Unfair doesn't make it untrue.
用户在向好友发送消息后
消息在限定时间后
会彻底的从好友设备及软件服务器上删除
阅后即焚
选手德发来消息
卢斯
Luce...
我还得早起参加训练呢
I have to get up early for practice in the morning.
晚安  艾米
Good night, Amy.
卢斯·埃德加
好友
斯蒂芬妮·金
你与斯蒂芬妮·金不是脸书好友
卢斯  我是斯蒂芬妮
Hey, Luce, it's Stephanie.
我真讨厌这样
I fucking hate it.
威尔逊说我就是一个女性默默忍受痛苦的例子
Wilson said I was an example of a woman suffering in silence.
所以大家又开始八卦了
So everyone is gossiping again.
你让我们暂时分开也许是对的
You were probably right for us to take a break.
我只是想像以前那样跟你聊天
I just wish we could talk like we used to.
再见
Bye.
你看上去不一样了
You look different.
新接发
New weave.
哪种的
What kind?
印度的
Indian.
-谢谢  -给你
- Thank you. - Here you go.
他们现在让你吃什么药
What do they have you taking now?
氯氮平
Clozapine.
让我汗流浃背
Makes me sweat like the devil.
哈丽特
Harriet,
这是什么
what is this?
希腊酸奶
That's Greek yogurt.
尝尝
Just taste it.
好吧
All right.
还行啊  不好吃
It's good, no!
你看起来那么...
You looked so...
这早餐还差不多
Now this what I call breakfast.
闭嘴吧  你什么时候拒绝过培根
Shut your mouth. Since when you ever turn down some bacon?
我知道这东西我们吃了一辈子了  但是
I know we ate this our whole lives but,
这速食产品里面全是毒药
this instant shit's made of poison.
我都不知道我们是怎么活下来的
I don't know how we made it through.
罗斯
Rose?
威尔逊老师
Ms. Wilson?
-你认识哈丽特  -威尔逊老师是我的老师
- You know Harriet? - Ms. Wilson's my teacher.
这个世界真小啊
Ain't the world tiny and great!
我是来给募捐活动买零食的
I just came here to pick up snacks for the fundraiser.
这个年轻人刚刚在跟我说
This young man was just telling me
什么旧石器时代饮食
about something called paleo.
是一种模仿穴居人的饮食
It's a diet, how the cavemen ate.
穴居人的寿命可不长  卢斯
Cavemen didn't live long, Luce.
但我打赌他们死的时候都有八块腹肌
Well, I bet they went out with great abs.
他是不是很可爱
Ain't he the cutest?
威尔逊老师
Ms. Wilson,
罗斯玛丽应该来参加我们学校的文化月庆典
Rosemary should come to our Culture Month Gala at school.
我要发表演讲
I'm giving a speech.
-是吗  -是的
- Is that right? - Yeah.
我平时没什么机会出门
I don't normally get to go places,
要是我能去就太好了
so that would be a treat for me.
她应该来参加  对吧  威尔逊老师
She should come. Right, Ms. Wilson?
我们可以商量一下
We'll talk about it.
好吧
Cool.
很高兴认识你  罗斯玛丽
It was nice meeting you, Rosemary.
希望到时候你能来
And, um, I hope you can make it.
我也是
Me too!
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
卢斯算哪门子黑人名字
What kind of black name is Luce?
彼得
Hey, Pete.
彼得  你想抱会儿他吗
Pete, you want to give him a whirl?
那是谁  那是谁
Who is that? Who is that?
谢谢  我真的很高兴你们俩能来
Thank you. I'm really glad you guys could make it.
你好吗
How you doing?
到底要我告诉你几遍  不行
How many times do I have to tell you no?
你得跟小孩子讲话了
You have to start talking to a little kid.
这他妈就是洗车  你想争辩什么
It's a fucking car wash. What are you arguing about?
他来这干什么
What the hell's he doing here?
听着  不许参加队里的活动
Come on, man, look. No team events.
-这是  -这事已经跟你解释过了
- It's a... - This has been explained to you.
我不会为了洗车这种事跟你争辩的
Bro, I'm not arguing with you over no car wash.
-你什么毛病  -这是队伍的募捐活动
- What's your problem? - It's a fundraiser for the team.
教练里夫斯  我的错  我邀请的德肖恩
Coach Reeves, it's my fault. I invited Deshaun.
我没意识到这也违反了
I didn't realize it violated
他与学校达成的协议
the terms of his agreement with the school.
你介意我俩在他走之前讨论一下作业吗
Do you mind if we talk about an assignment real quick before he goes?
尽快说完就行
As long as it's quick.
-好  谢谢教练  -走吧  哥们
- Cool. Thanks, Coach. - Come on, bro.
-这事不好意思  -不  让他去死吧
- Sorry about that. - No, fuck his bitch ass, man.
那个老黑总是在打压我  从第一天起就这样
That nigga always undermining with me, bro, from day one.
没了你我们的长跑项目都弱爆了
Well we're getting killed on these distance events without you, bro.
科里跑得根本不行
Corey can't run for shit.
除非终点线那有小骚逼等着他
unless there's pussy waiting at the finish line.
说不好  要是像她姐姐那样的小骚逼的话
Don't know. If it's anything like his sister's pussy,
那玩意可不干净
that shit got stains on it.
我听说了
So I've heard.
你和迈克·杰夫斯怎么回事
What's going on with you and Mike Jeffs?
我看见你和他还有他的小弟们在一块
I've been seeing you hanging around with him and his boys.
我不知道你们关系都那么好了
I didn't know you all were tight like that.
说不好  我又不是未来的诺贝尔奖得主
I don't know. It ain't like future Nobel Laureates and shit.
不是诺贝尔奖得主
You don't have to be a Nobel Laureate
也知道迈克·杰夫斯不是什么好东西
to know that Mike Jeffs is bad news, bro.
你为什么跟他们扯上关系了
Why you getting mixed up with those guys?
搞什么  淡定好吗  我没事
What the fuck? Chill out, all right? I'm good.
靠  你还要管我裤子提的不够高吗
Damn, my pants too low, too?
我要想有所成就就一定要把裤子提好吗
I gotta hike them up if I want to make something of myself?
老黑  你不要对我指手画脚的
Na, my nigga, don't come over here and try to patronize me.
别这样  哥们
Come on, man.
我不知道你是不是忙着应付威尔逊
I don't know if you've been busy distracted
还有这些个虚伪小人全天候捧你臭脚
with Wilson and the rest of these fake-ass motherfuckers
但是我跟你们没关系了  哥们
sucking your dick 24/7 but my shit is done, bro.
结束了
It's finished.
事实上  有多少次我们是一起抽的  卢斯
As a matter of fact, how many time we smoke together, Luce?
卢斯  有多少次是你来我家抽大麻的
Luce, how many times you come to my crib and blaze?
威尔逊在我的储物柜里找到了大麻  我被踢出队
Wilson finds weed in my locker and now I'm off the team.
我的奖学金没了
That's my scholarship gone.
为什么是我  不是你
Why me and not you, my nigga?
回答我的问题  为什么是我而不是你
Answer the question. Why me and not you?
-我不知道  -你不知道
- I don't know. - You don't know.
你明明知道我在说什么
You exactly know exactly what the fuck I'm talking about.
因为他们想让你赢
It's because they want you to win.
否则的话  他们那些自强自立的屁话
Otherwise, all their little up by your own bootstraps bullshit,
就不适用了
it don't apply.
但话说回来  我瞎说什么呢
But then again, why am I trippin'?
至少要有一个奥巴马  对吧
Gotta have at least one Obama, right?
这不是我求来的  哥们
I didn't ask for this, man.
不是你求来的
You didn't ask for this.
那你想跟我交换吗
So, what, you want to trade or something?
我就知道你不想
Yeah, I didn't think so.
德肖恩
Deshaun...
我想弥补这一切
I want to make this right.
罗
Ro?
天啊
God.
不  不
No, no...
我刚才
I was...
我刚才在走路  我想走到那边去  然后
I was walking and I was trying to make it there and then...
食物  食物就
the food, the food was...
-我来收拾  我来收拾  -没事的
- I'll clean it. I'll clean up. - You're okay.
我来收拾
I'll clean it up.
深呼吸  深呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
没事  请坐吧
No. Please, sit.
他们搞错了  我点的卡布奇诺
They screwed up the order. I asked for cappuccinos
然后给我们的是星冰乐
and they gave us Frappuccinos.
-我更喜欢这个  -是吗
- I like these more. - You do?
我至少要喝三杯  否则都撑不到吃晚饭
Can't make it to the dinner without at least three of them.
好吧
Okay.
-谢谢你  -不  应该谢谢你来
- Thank you. - No, thank you for, um,
见我  你肯定觉得有点奇怪
meeting me. This must be a little weird.
的确
It is.
好吧  有件和卢斯有关的事
Okay. Um, yeah, well I guess I was hoping you could help me with
我希望你能帮个忙
something to do with Luce.
我们其实没什么来往了
We don't really talk a lot anymore.
-是吗  -自从分手之后
- You don't? - Not since we broke up.
什么
What?
你不知道我们分手了吗
You didn't know we broke up?
我不知道你们交往过
I didn't know you dated.
交往了多久
For how long?
埃德加夫人
Mrs. Edgar,
跟你说我和卢斯的事  我有点不自在
I don't feel comfortable telling you about me and Luce.
当然
Yeah, of course.
因为我不清楚你为什么想知道
Because I don't know why you want to know.
-好的  我来解释一下  -好
- Okay. Let me explain myself. - Yeah.
-这和哈丽特·威尔逊有关  -什么
- This is about Harriet Wilson. - What?
我需要知道她对你做了什么
I need to know what she did to you.
因为卢斯告诉我们
Because Luce told us
她发现派对上出了什么事情之后
that when she found out what happened at the party...
卢斯发誓他不会告诉任何人派对上出了什么事
Luce swore he wouldn't tell what happened at the party.
我还以为他不知道出了什么事呢
I thought he didn't know what happened.
我该走了
I should go.
不  等等  斯蒂芬妮  求你了
No, wait. Stephanie, please.
听我说
Listen to me.
我只想知道真相  好吗
I just want to know the truth, Okay?
如果威尔逊老师让你觉得发生的那些事情
Now, if Ms. Wilson made you feel like whatever happened
应该变成什么政治宣言
should be some kind of a political statement,
那她就错了
then that's wrong of her.
作为女人  我们需要做的就是互相支持
As women what we need to do is support each other.
你懂吗
Do you understand?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
我想要支持你
I want to support you.
你理应得到支持
You deserve to be supported.
好吧
Okay.
但是在我支持你之前  我需要知道出了什么事
But for me to do that I need to know what happened.
说得轻松
It's easy to say that.
但是一旦你知道了  就不能当作不知道了
But once you know something, you can't un-know it.
我想知道  不管是什么
I want to know, no matter what.
拜托
Please.
康复中心
哈丽特  求你了
Harriet, please...
对不起  我想不出别的解决办法了
I'm sorry. I just can't think of any other way to resolve this.
你患有精神疾病  罗
You suffer from a condition, Ro.
很明显我家已经不是个理想的环境了
And it's clear my home is no longer an ideal environment.
你听起来就像那些医生
You sound like one of them doctors
她又要丢下我了
she about to dump me with again.
-我不是要丢下你  -是吗
- I'm not dumping you. - Oh really?
感觉你就是要丢下我  哈丽特
That's what it feels like, Harriet!
别这样
Come on, now.
别闹了  别闹了
Don't make a scene. Don't make a scene.
哈丽特
Harriet!
-罗  -没事  没事
- Ro... - It's fine. It's fine.
没事  没事
It's fine, it's fine...
没事
It's fine!
哈丽特
Harriet!
欧力基办了个派对
Orlicki had a party.
我喝多了
I was drunk.
我和两个朋友一起去的  我们三个都喝多了
I had gone with two friends. All three of us were drunk.
千万别告诉别人  太难堪了
Please don't tell anyone this, it's embarrassing.
不  就我们两个知道  我保证
No, no, this is between us. I promise.
大家一直在喝一种像糖浆一样的东西
People kept having shots of stuff that tasted like syrup,
我一直在喝  因为很轻松
and I just kept drinking it because it was easy.
但是我感到头晕
but I got dizzy.
跟朋友走丢了
I lost my friends.
欧力基找到我  让我去地下室里躺一会
Orlicki found me and told me to go lie down in the basement.
那里很黑
It was dark.
我看不见
I couldn't see.
我摸索着走到沙发那里
I felt my way over to the couch
但是那里有人
but there were people there.
接下来  有人说我们应该玩圣诞老人游戏
Next thing, I knew someone said we should play the Santa Claus game.
那是什么
What's that?
就是他们玩的傻帽游戏
It's this stupid game that guys play
把女孩从一个人的大腿上传到另一个人的大腿上
where a girl gets passed around from lap to lap
根据女孩允许他们上下其手的程度
and depending on how far she lets them go
或者他们有多喜欢你坐在他们腿上
or how much they like you sitting on them,
他们给你打分  一声到三声
they rate you from one to three.
嚯嚯嚯
Ho ho hos.
我的天  这不是真的吧
My God, that can't be real.
还有比这还恶劣的游戏
There are worse games.
总之
Anyway,
他们开始把我传来传去
they started passing me around.
我一直在想  天呐
I kept thinking, "God,
万一我现在吐了怎么办
what if I throw up right now?
那得多难堪啊
How embarrassing would that be?"
开始的时候  他们在笑
When they started, they were laughing.
但是时间越久
But the longer it went on...
我越觉得这游戏永远都不会结束了
And it felt like it went on forever.
我只能听到呼吸声
All I could hear was breathing.
呼吸
Breathing,
计数
and counting.
一  二
One, two,
二
two,
三
three...
一  二
One, two...
在某一时刻
At some point
我绝对说了
I definitely said
想让他们停下来
I wanted them to stop.
但也许听起来像是开玩笑
But maybe it sounded like I was joking
或者我只是在脑子里对自己说的
or maybe it was just something I said to myself in my head...
到处都是手
There were hands everywhere.
感觉像是  他们要把我吞噬掉
It was like they were swallowing me.
有时候在他们的大腿上
And sometimes in their laps
我可以感觉到...
I could feel...
真恶心
Gross.
我再醒过来的时候  卢斯在我身旁
When I woke up, Luce was there.
他说他看到并叫停了他们
He said he found them and told them to stop.
然后就一直跟我待在一起
And he stayed with me the rest of the night.
有没有可能...
Is it possible that...?
卢斯也参与其中了
Was Luce one of the guys?
他不会那么做的
He wouldn't do that.
-但他...  -他就是不会
- But he... - He just wouldn't.
威尔逊老师是怎么回事
What happened with Ms. Wilson?
当时有很多谣言
There were a lot of rumors.
与此同时
It was at the same time
德肖恩·米克斯被踢出了校队
Deshaun Meeks got kicked off the team
因为威尔逊老师在他的储物柜里发现了大麻
because Wilson found weed in his locker.
她搜了德肖恩的储物柜吗
She searched Deshaun's locker?
然后还叫了警察
And called the cops.
我不想报警  我能说什么
I didn't want that. What would I say?
我什么都想不起来了
I couldn't remember anything
而且我肯定没跟大家说我喝醉了啊
and I definitely didn't tell everyone I was drunk.
卢斯怎么说的
What did Luce say?
他说我不出声是对的
He said I was right not to tell.
因为他要保护自己的朋友们吗
Because he was protecting his friends?
因为他要保护我
Because he was protecting me.
他不想逼我做任何我不情愿做的事
He didn't want me to do anything I didn't want to do.
你俩为什么分手
Why did you two break up?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我很想他
I miss him.
他是我有史以来最好的男友
He's the best boyfriend I ever had.
斯蒂芬妮...
Stephanie...
对发生的事我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry for what happened.
不用抱歉
Don't be.
现在都没事了
Everything is fine now.
你去哪了
Where were you?
急诊病人
Emergency patient.
是吗
Oh, really?
-凯伦看起来挺好的  -是挺好的
- Karen seems good. - Yeah, she is.
他们很幸福
They're happy.
那孩子动个不停
The baby fidgets.
小孩子就是这样的
I think that's just a baby thing.
你喝醉了吗
Are you drunk?
所以不是只有那个孩子会那样
So you don't think it's that baby in particular.
我怎么会知道
How would I know?
我们又没生过小孩  所以...
I mean, I don't know, so...
我怎么会知道
how would I know?
是啊
Yeah.
是吧
Right?
是啊  你说得没错
Yeah, I guess you wouldn't.
是啊
No.
你没机会给自己的小孩换尿布
You know, it's not Luce's fault
并不是卢斯的错
you were denied diaper changing privileges.
没错
No.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们做出了选择
Look, we made a choice.
只要你承认我们付出了代价  我就没意见
I'm okay with that as long as you recognize it cost us.
意思是
Which means?
曾经我确实想要不一样的生活
I did want something different once.
十年过去了  你却深陷其中
Ten years and you're trapped.
这是你说的
Your words.
你自己说的  你想要不一样的生活
Well, you said it. You wanted something different.
-是的  -比如呢
- I did, yeah. - Like what?
我为我们的儿子感到骄傲
Look, I'm proud of our son.
我爱他  我对他的爱
Okay, I love him. I love him
远远超出我自己的理解  好吗
more than I'll ever understand, okay?
但我们花费了数年时间带他治疗
But we spent years with him in therapy
还有康复
and rehabilitation.
我们的朋友们无法理解
Our friends couldn't understand
为什么我们不能自己生个孩子
why we didn't just have a kid of our own.
所以当他们忙着做那些
And so while they fell away doing
正常人做的事
what normal fucking people do,
我们拼尽全力给他创造一个天地
we worked our asses off to give him a life,
而代价就是我们自己的生活
at the expense of our own.
所以假装我们毫无牺牲鬼都不信
So to pretend that that didn't cost us anything is bullshit.
我没假装
I wasn't pretending.
你就是在假装  艾米
You are! Amy.
你就是
You are.
你如此渴望他成长为
You want so desperately for him
你心目中的样子
to be what you want him to be,
你故意忽视眼前发生的事
you're ignoring what's right in front of you.
无论他是什么样的人  都是我们的儿子
What he is, is our son.
没错
Right.
这是无法改变的事实
And nothing's going to change that.
没错
Right.
所以...
So...
去它的
fuck this.
去你的
Fuck you.
我来到这里
I came here,
来到美国
to America,
来到这所学校
to this school,
然后找到了自我
and I found myself.
第一次见到我母亲的时候  她不会念我的名字
When I first met my mother, she couldn't pronounce my name.
她一遍又一遍的尝试
She tried over and over to get the emphasis
想找准音节的重音  但是
on the syllables correct, but...
她就是不会念
she just couldn't.
所以我父亲提议给我改名
So my father suggested that they rename me.
他们选了卢斯这个名字
They picked Luce,
然后...
and, uh...
我在考虑今晚演讲的内容时
I thought about that when I was figuring out
想到了这件事
what to say to you all tonight.
我意识到身为美国人我是多么幸运
And I realized how lucky I am to be an American.
因为在这里我有重新开始的机会
Because here I got the chance to start over.
我可以重新定义自己
To redefine myself.
在这里我们可以选择自己的人生  在这里...
Here we can be who we choose. Here...
还记得那年生日我们送给他的那条鱼吗
Remember that fish we got him for his birthday?
-丹尼斯  -是的
- Dennis. - Yeah, that's right.
可怜的丹尼斯
Yeah. Poor Dennis.
他把鱼捞出来
Yeah. The way he just pulled him out
扔到房间另一头
and threw him across the room like that.
就像扔一片肉一样
Like a piece of deli meat.
"我只是想看它飞起来的样子  妈妈"
"I just wanted to see him fly, mom."
我们没有搞砸  对吧
We didn't screw up, did we?
没有
No.
一切都没问题
Everything's fine.
阅后即焚
斯蒂芬妮·金发来消息
斯蒂芬妮
你妈人很好  我感觉好多了
我
那就好  对了  德答应了
斯蒂芬妮
我们得谈谈
用暗号说话是什么意思呢
So, what does it mean to speak in code?
这能让你分辨出特定的群体
Well, it tells you about a particular group.
有共同词汇的必要性
The necessity to have a shared vocabulary.
抱歉
Sorry.
在社会中有共同斗争的必要性
To have common struggles in a society.
语言是一条纽带
You see, language is a bond.
它将我们每个人区分开来  但更重要的是
It's how we tell each other apart, but more importantly,
它将我们团结在一起
it's how we stick together.
不好意思  威尔逊老师
Excuse me, Ms. Wilson,
我需要你跟我来一趟
I need you to come with me please.
快
Right now.
我姐姐在哪
Where's my sister?
她在这工作  她就在这
She works here. She is here.
-罗斯玛丽  -我姐姐呢
- Rosemary! - Where's my sister?
罗斯玛丽  我就在这  就在这
Rosemary! I'm right here. I'm right here.
走吧  我们回家吧
Now come on, let's go home.
-你家不欢迎我  -不是的
- You don't want me at home. - That's not true.
你不...你以我为耻
You won't... You're ashamed of me.
不是的
I am not.
你恨我
You... You hate me.
-别胡说了  罗  -你恨我
- Don't talk nonsense, Ro. - You hate me.
-你恨我  -看着我
- You hate me. - Look at me.
手机都放下
Put those phones away.
你觉得丢脸了  你觉得丢脸了
You're embarrassed. You're embarrassed!
-你觉得丢脸了  -停下
- You're embarrassed! - Stop this!
立刻停下  罗斯
Stop it right now, Rose!
她觉得丢脸了  觉得我丢她脸了
She's embarrassed! She's embarrassed of me!
你觉得我丢你脸了
You're embarrassed of me!
我是你的黑人老妹
I am your black nigger bitch sister!
我是你的血亲  不是这些白人
This your blood. Not these white folk.
我是你的血亲  你是甩不掉的
I am your blood. You can't get rid of blood.
你无法甩掉血脉  我是你妹妹  你...
You can't run from blood! I am your sister! You...
-她是病人  警官  -别跑
- She's-she's sick, officers. - Don't run!
冷静下来
Relax! Calm down!
冷静
Relax.
放开我  放开我
Get off of me! Get off of me!
-冷静  -放开我
- Calm down. - Get off of me!
冷静下来  否则我电击你了
Relax or you'll be tased.
-冷静  -放开我
- Calm down. - Get off of me!
我要电击你了
I'm going to tase you!
-请冷静  -放开我
- Calm down! Please! - Relax!
求你了
Please.
不
No!
哈丽特  哈丽特  哈丽特
Harriet, Harriet...Harriet!
冷静
Calm down!
能给她披件衣服吗
Can you cover her up?
你们能给她披件衣服吗
Can you please just cover her up?
放下手机  立刻回教室
Put the phones down. Get back to class now.
手机给我  快点
Give me your phone. Come on!
这里每个人的手机
I want every single phone in this hallway
都交到我办公室
in my office right now.
所有手机
Every cell phone!
天啊  我这辈子都没见过这样的事
My God! I've never seen anything like it in my entire life.
太疯狂了
It was insane.
谁能想到威尔逊老师的家人是疯子
Who knew that Ms. Wilson's family was so fucked up?
我是你的黑人老妹
I am your black, nigger...
-这是今天发生的吗  -是的  很疯狂吧
- This was today? - Yeah, it's crazy, huh?
天啊
Oh my God!
-不是吧  -操
- Oh, come on. - Oh, fuck.
哈丽特在哪
Where's Harriet?
我觉得她和她妹妹
I think she spent most of the day
今天大半天都在警局里
at the police station with her sister.
不过证明了
Just goes to show you.
证明了什么
What?
没什么  就是...
Nothing, it's just...
你永远不知道人们在经历什么
You never really know what's going on with people.
生活中不为人知的那一面
Like, in life. Outside of what you know.
我不应该说她是个婊子的
I shouldn't have said she was a bitch.
卢斯  我觉得我欠你一个道歉
Well, I think I owe you an apology, Luce.
-为什么  -真的
- For what? - Really.
你从来没有给我任何理由怀疑你的诚实
You've never given me any reason to doubt your integrity.
你应该知道  我们支持你
You should know we got your back.
-无论发生什么吗  -无论发生什么  小混蛋
- No matter what? - No matter what. Asshole.
放下手机  立刻回教室
Put your phones down, get back to class now.
黑鬼婊子
谁啊
Who is it?
我得跟你谈谈卢斯
I need to talk to you about Luce.
哈丽特  如果你上网搜索"模范学生"
Harriet, if you Googled "model student"
卢斯·埃德加的照片就会跳出来
Luce Edgar's picture would come up on the computer
而你要跟我说这孩子在你房子外涂鸦了
and now you're telling me that this kid, graffiti-ed your home?
不仅仅是涂鸦  丹
It's not just the graffiti, Dan.
嗯  他还写了一篇令人不安的论文
No, he also wrote an upsetting paper.
-论文中他主张暴力...  -这篇论文
- In which he argued violence... - A paper
你手上已经没有存档了
that you no longer have a copy of.
我交给她妈妈了
I gave it to his mother.
这篇令人不安的论文
An upsetting paper where it sounds
只不过是他按照作业要求完成的
like he did exactly what the assignment asked him to do.
我明白误解和挑衅之间的区别
I know the difference between miscommunication and provocation.
我能分得清楚
I can tell the difference between them.
有没有这种可能
Isn't there a chance, just maybe,
他写的东西超出了你的理解范围
that what he wrote just went over your head?
我不是在挖苦你
I don't mean that as a dig.
拜托  我认为你很有才华
Come on, I think you're brilliant.
你善于表达  你是个出色的老师
I think you're articulate, you're a great teacher,
但你也知道  我们都会时不时地看走眼
but you know, we all misread signals from time to time.
有一项性侵犯的指控
There's an allegation of sexual assault.
一名学生来找我说
A student came to me and said
卢斯在派对上对她进行了性侵犯
Luce sexually assaulted her at a party.
-哪个学生  -丹
- Which student? - Dan...
你说的可是犯罪
You're talking about a crime now.
我不会因为你这些毫无根据的指控和直觉
I'm not gonna ruin a kid's life because you come here
就毁了一个孩子的人生
with some unsubstantiated accusations and hunches.
那就让我证明给你看
Then let me prove it.
怎么了
Hey, what's up?
之前我还不相信  但也许你是对的
I didn't buy it before but maybe you're right,
也许她真的对卢斯抱有奇怪的恨意
maybe she has some kind of weird vendetta thing for Luce.
等一下
Okay, hold on.
你没能让她如愿
She doesn't get what she wants out of you
于是她就来找我了
so then she comes to me.
还是不成功  他就去找丹了
Then when that doesn't work she goes to Dan.
她自己的生活出现危机  却拿我们的儿子出气
She's having a personal crisis, she's taking it out on our son.
让我来处理  让我来
Just let me handle it. Just let me.
-好吧  -好  再见
- Okay. - Okay. Bye.
你回家做什么
What are you doing home?
我只是
I, uh,
去训练前回来拿几样东西
just needed to pick up a few things before practice.
-你看了丹发来的电邮吗  -看了
- You see Dan's email? - Yeah.
不知道到底是什么事
I'm not sure what it's about.
看来只能等着瞧了
I guess we'll just wait and see.
是啊
Guess so.
我接受了你的建议
I'm, um, I'm taking your advice you know.
什么建议
About what?
演讲
The speech.
我准备谈谈自己  你应该会很骄傲的
I'm making it more personal. I think you'll be proud.
一定会的
I'm sure I will be.
那个
So, um,
谈话的时候见
I'll see you at the meeting.
-六点整  -对
- Six o'clock sharp. - Great.
你为什么不告诉我你跟斯蒂芬妮谈过了
Why didn't you tell me you talked to Stephanie?
你觉得她不会告诉我吗
You didn't think she would tell me?
我觉得我们两个都没有
I don't think either of us have been great
把所有事情告诉对方  卢斯
at keeping each other in the loop, Luce.
你想证明什么
What are you trying to prove?
你想隐瞒什么
What are you trying to hide?
我没有隐瞒任何事
I'm not trying to hide anything.
我从斯蒂芬妮那里听到的不是这样的
That's not the impression I got from Stephanie.
-她说什么了吗  -你说呢
- What did she say? - You tell me.
找她谈的人是你
You're the one that talked to her.
-停下  -停什么
- Stop it. - Stop what?
-这个游戏  -什么游戏
- This game. - What game?
-你对那个女孩做了什么  -怎么  你认为我
- What did you do to that girl? - What, you think I...?
别管我怎么想  你对她做了什么
Never mind what I think. What did you do to her?
-我做了正确的是  -通过撒谎吗
- I did the right thing. - By lying?
-她威胁说要自杀  -通过保护
- She threatened to kill herself. - By protecting...
威尔逊老师一直在逼她
Ms. Wilson kept pushing for her...
通过保护伤害她的人吗
By protecting the people who hurt her?
我只是想让她好起来
I just wanted her to get better.
那你为什么不求助
Then why didn't you ask for help?
-她在好转  -我认为你在撒谎
- She was getting better. - I think you're lying.
-我没撒谎  -跟我说实话
- I'm not lying. - Tell me the truth.
-我说的就是实话  -别再骗我了
- I'm telling you the truth. - Stop lying to me.
-我没撒谎  我没撒谎  -给我说实话
- I'm not lying. I'm not lying! - Tell me the fucking truth!
你为什么要写那篇论文
Why did you write that paper?
如果我告诉你那是我相信的理念呢
What if I told you it's what I believed?
你相信
You believe in
通过伤人来表明观点
hurting people to make a point?
你不知道  你根本没读  对吧
You wouldn't know. You never read it, right?
卢斯  我...
Luce, I...
我觉得
I feel like...
你们都在等着我证实一件事
you're all waiting for me to confirm this thing...
一件没人愿意大声说出来的事
that no one wants to say aloud.
我拼命努力
And I'm trying so hard
不想证实那件事
not to be that.
但过了一段时间  你就会情不自禁地想
But after a while you can't help but think that maybe
-也许一切都是徒劳  -你在说什么
- you're fighting a losing battle. - What do you mean?
我在说
I mean
我只能成为圣人或者恶魔
it's like I only get to be a saint or a monster.
不是这样的  不管你是谁
That's not true. We always accepted you
我们一直都接纳你
for whoever you are.
我不相信你  艾米
I don't believe you, Amy.
而且我觉得我要窒息了  我喘不上气
And I feel like I'm suffocating. Like I can't breathe.
所以有我在啊  我来帮助你保护你
That's why I'm here, to help you and to protect you.
如果你正是我需要保护的原因之一呢
What if you're part of what I need protecting from?
我要迟到了
I'm gonna be late, um...
谈话的时候见
I'll see you at the meeting.
将军队
我保证会尽量减少痛苦
I promise it'll be as painless as possible.
我们就在走廊那头
We'll be just down the hall.
等时候到了  我会护送你进去
When the time comes, I'll escort you in and
你只要把你告诉我的告诉他们就行了
you just tell them what you told me.
然后你就没事了
And then that's it, you're done.
卢斯会在场吗
Luce will be there?
你说话的时候  我可以让他回避
I can have him step out when it's time for you to speak.
那他妈妈呢
What about his mom?
她会在场
She'll be there.
是的
Yes.
你很勇敢
You're brave.
因为你今天展现了勇气
It's because you show courage today, that
明天就不会有别人和你有一样的遭遇了
someone else doesn't suffer like you did tomorrow.
你明白吗
You understand?
那就好
Good.
很好
五  六  七  八
Five, six, seven, eight.
稍息
Parade rest.
♪ 什么 ♪
♪ What? ♪
♪ 你的机会来了 ♪
♪ It's your time! ♪
♪ 一  二 ♪
♪ One! Two! ♪
♪ 我们能行 ♪
♪ Yes, we can! ♪
♪ 什么 ♪
♪ What? ♪
立正
A-ten hut!
二  三  四  定
Two, three, four... boom!
你们好  进来吧
Hey, guys. Come on in.
你好吗  艾米
How you doing, Amy?
你好吗  彼得  很高兴见到你
How you doing, Peter? Good to see you.
-丹  -丹
- Hey, Dan. - Dan.
-你们怎么样  -不太好
- You all right? - Been better.
-诊所怎么样  -很忙  总是很忙
- How's the clinic? - Busy. Always busy.
-忙是好事  -是啊
- Busy is good. - Yeah.
忙总是好的
Busy is always good.
她来了
Here she is.
哈丽特·威尔逊
Harriet Wilson.
你认识彼得和艾米·埃德加
You know Peter and Amy Edgar.
-彼得  艾米  很高兴见到你们  -我们也是
- Good to see you, Amy. Peter. - Good to see you, too.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
现在只剩  风云人物没来了
So we're just, uh, missing the man of the hour here.
他应该快到了
He should be along here.
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
-我忘记时间了  -训练到忘记时间
- I lost track of time. - Lost track at the track.
果然是我了解的卢斯
Sounds like the Luce I know.
-你好吗  -我很好  谢谢  陶森校长
- How are you? - I'm great. Thanks, Principal Towson.
-你好吗  -陶森校长
- How are you? - Principal Towson.
快毕业了就变得这么正经
Notice he's all formal now that he's a senior.
准备去上大学了  对吧
Getting ready for college, right?
-没错  -聪明人  聪明人
- That's right. - Smart man. Smart man.
请坐  各位  我们坐吧
Have a seat, guys. Come on, sit down.
-那么  -我想
- So... - I'd like to...
不吉利
Jinx!
你先请
Go ahead. You first.
那我先说最重要的
Well, I guess first things first.
我们之间有一系列的误解
There have been a series of miscommunications
我认为与其试图解决这些问题
and I think rather than try to hash all that out,
不如承认我和卢斯之间
it's probably more productive to just acknowledge
已经出现了一些摩擦
some tension has developed between Luce and me.
这种事时有发生
It happens.
双方的意思被误解
Signals get crossed and
我们必须想办法解开误会
we have to find a way to untangle the knots,
即使我们不清楚最开始误会是如何出现的
even if we're not sure how those knots got there in first place.
说得没错  还有
Definitely. And...
我只是想为让你
I just want to apologize
感到不被尊重而道歉
for making you feel disrespected.
这学期我肩上的担子很重
I've taken on a lot this semester,
我知道这不是借口  真的不是
and not that that's an excuse, it's not but...
但我最近的表现不佳  为此我道歉
I haven't been my best self lately and I'm sorry for that.
-谢谢你  卢斯  -不客气
- Thank you, Luce. - You're welcome.
目前为止  我觉得进展非常顺利
This is going really well, I think, so far.
我们来谈谈威胁吧
Let's talk about the threat.
我也为此道歉  威尔逊老师
I'm sorry for that too, Ms. Wilson.
什么
Sorry?
你这是承认吗
Are you admitting it now?
就像我说的
Like I was saying,
考虑到我最近的压力
given the stress I've been under,
我说的话听起来肯定有点...
I'm sure what I said sounded a bit...
不不不  不好意思  这不是压力导致的
No, no, no. I'm sorry, but this isn't about some
语气不善的问题
stress-induced problem of tone.
这是一个人暗示
This is about one person
对另一个人施加暴力
suggesting violence against another.
-你说什么  -你当时不在场  埃德加
- Excuse me? - You weren't there, Mr. Edgar.
有些互动必须亲身经历
There are interactions that must be experienced
才能理解其中的意图
in order to appreciate their intent.
无意冒犯
Respectfully,
我认为你应该更加慎重地措辞
I think you should choose your words more carefully.
-我儿子刚刚道歉了  -真的吗
- My son has just apologized. - Has he?
哈丽特  我觉得为了让谈话进行下去
I-I think in the interest of moving forward, Harriet,
我觉得你承认卢斯确实道歉了会比较有帮助
it would be helpful for you to acknowledge Luce did in fact apologize.
你昨晚在哪里
Where were you last night?
-什么  -我家被人破坏了
- What? - My home was vandalized.
-等一下  -我想知道从放学
- Just a second... - I want to know where you were
到我回家期间你在哪里
between when school let out and I got back to my house.
-我出去了  -去哪里了
- I was out. - Where?
我儿子被指控犯罪了吗
Is my son being accused of a crime?
他马上就要被指控了
He sure as hell is about to be.
如果他被指控了
Because if he is,
如果他被指控犯罪了
if he is being accused of a crime,
那我要请律师
I want a lawyer.
爸  没事的  我什么都没做
Dad, It's fine. I didn't do anything.
这个女人的妹妹
This woman's sister,
这个女人的妹妹刚刚经历了众目睽睽之下的
this woman's sister has just gone through a very public
-精神崩溃  -好了
- mental breakdown. - All right.
你怎么知道不是她干的
How do you know she's not responsible?
-我妹妹不会那么做  -我儿子也不会
- My sister wouldn't do that. - Well, neither would my son.
好了  好了
All right, okay.
大家冷静...卢斯
Everybody just... Luce,
你能帮帮我们吗
can you help us out here?
你能告诉我们昨天放学后你去哪了吗
Can you tell us where you were after school yesterday?
-我不想说  -你去哪了
- I don't want to say. - Where were you?
-和朋友在一起  -哪些朋友
- With friends. - Who?
看  她在撒谎  丹
See, he's lying, Dan.
哈丽特
Harriet!
陶森校长  我可以解释我去哪了
Principal Towson, I can explain where I was
但我不想给别人惹上麻烦
but I do not want to get people in trouble.
我尊重你的谨慎  但是
I respect your discretion, but,
卢斯  你妈妈  你爸爸  威尔逊老师
Luce, your mom, your dad, Ms. Wilson,
我们都只是想弄明白是怎么回事  好吗
we're all just trying to pin down what's going on here, okay?
如果你知道些什么  如果你能帮助我们
And if you know anything, if you could help us with that,
这对你只有好处
it's-it's only going to help you.
这让我很难堪
It's embarrassing for me.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding.
哈丽特
Harriet.
说吧  卢斯
Go ahead, Luce.
请不要告诉任何人我给你看了这个
Please don't tell anyone I'm showing you this.
这是背叛朋友
It's a violation of trust.
约翰逊  二十小时前
飞叶子
怎么着
What up?
我不想给他们惹上麻烦
I don't want them to get in trouble.
没人惹上麻烦
No one's gonna get in trouble.
你们都是好孩子
All right, you guys are good kids.
-我们都知道  -这都是放屁
- We all know that. - This is bullshit.
哈丽特  失陪一下
Harriet. Excuse me.
哈丽特
Harriet!
将军队
斯蒂芬...
Steph...
我认为那所大学对你来说是个很好的选择
I think that's a really good choice for you.
我知道你最初没有把它纳入考虑  但我...
I know it wasn't on your original list, but I...
是你让她来找我的
You told her to come to me.
-什么  -你告诉了她该说什么
- I'm sorry? - You told her what to say.
丹  她在说什么
Dan, what is she talking about?
请解释一下  哈丽特
Please explain what your're talking about, Harriet.
我觉得威尔逊老师最近遭遇了太多事
I think Ms. Wilson's just been through a lot.
先是她的妹妹精神崩溃
Between what's happened with her sister's breakdown
然后她的家又被人破坏
and someone vandalizing her house.
她糊涂了
She's confused.
对吧  威尔逊老师  你糊涂了
Right, Ms. Wilson? You're confused.
卢斯  我需要你回避一下
Luce, I'm going to need you to step out for a moment.
我还以为这次谈话的目的就是让大家
I thought this meeting was to get together
一起把事情搞清楚
and figure things out.
是的  但我需要和你的家长
Yes. But I need to speak with your parents
还有陶森校长单独谈  请配合
and Principal Towson alone. Please.
-好的  -不
- Sure. - No.
他可以留下
He can stay.
不管你要对我们说什么
Whatever you have to say to us,
都可以让他听着
you can say in front of him.
你儿子把非法烟花带进了学校
Your son brought illegal fireworks onto school property.
-什么  -我搜查了卢斯的储物柜
- Excuse me? - I searches Luce's locker
发现了非法烟花
and I found illegal fireworks.
你为什么没告诉我  哈丽特
Why didn't you tell me this, Harriet?
等一下  学生们共用储物柜  对吧
Well, hold on. The kids share lockers, right?
考虑到卢斯是模范学生  有人觉得
Well, it makes sense that given the kind of student Luce is
在他的储物柜里藏东西比较安全也不奇怪了
that someone would think his was the safe hiding place.
烟花是谁的都有可能
The fireworks could have belonged to anyone.
而且我已经吸取了教训
And I've learned my lesson.
我会把锁的密码换了
I'm going to change my combination
我们不会再共用储物柜了
and we won't share lockers anymore.
好的
Okay.
哈丽特  烟花现在在哪里
Harriet, where are the fireworks now?
艾米
Amy?
什么事
Yes?
烟花在哪里
Where are they?
-什么意思  -我交给你了
- What do you mean? - I gave them to you.
我不知道她在说什么
I don't know what she's talking about.
什么
What?
对  她打电话给我
Nope. She called me
声称她发现了烟花
and she claimed she found these fireworks.
声称我儿子威胁了她
She claimed my son threatened her.
-艾米  -然后她把我们
- Amy! - And then she drags us
拖到你面前  丹
down here in front of you, Dan,
并且威胁要对我儿子采取法律行动
and threatens legal action against my son
而他显然没有犯罪
for a crime he clearly didn't commit.
不好意思  闹剧可以结束了吗
I mean, I'm sorry, but are we done here?
我们能回到这个女人决定对我儿子
Can my son go back to being the student he was
进行某种疯狂的政治迫害之前吗
before this woman decided to go after him
回到之前让我儿子接着做模范学生
on some kind of insane witch hunt?
不  彼得
No, Peter...
我认为
I think
谈话结束了  哈丽特
we're done here, Harriet.
不不不  丹
No, no, no. Dan...
对  哈丽特
Yeah, Harriet.
谈话结束了
We're done.
我不想再听了
We are done.
艾米  彼得  谢谢你们能来
Amy, Peter, thank you for coming.
闹成这样我很抱歉  我会做出补偿的
I'm very sorry about this. I will make it up to you.
我保证  卢斯  谢谢你
I promise. Luce, thank you.
-晚安  陶森校长  -谢谢你
- Good night, Principal Towson. - Thank you.
好了  威尔逊老师
All right, Ms. Wilson...
丹
Dan,
斯蒂芬妮·金之前就在我办公室
Stephanie Kim was in my office.
-什么都别说  别说  -不  丹
- Just don't say anything. Don't say anything. - No, Dan...
我们明天会谈这事的
We're going to talk tomorrow. Okay?
-没关系  我们明天谈  -不
- It's okay, we'll talk tomorrow. - No.
要是你们饿了  我可以把剩菜热一热
I can heat up leftovers if anyone wants.
我不要
No, I'm good.
-他生我气了吗  -没有
- Is he mad at me? - No, he's fine.
他只是...
He's just...
你饿了吗
Are you hungry?
我应该抓紧准备演讲了
I should probably get to my speech.
好的  等不及想听了
Okay. Well, can't wait to hear it.
谢谢  艾米  晚安
Thanks, Amy. Good night.
闻起来真香
That smells good.
我也有一定的家庭生活能力
I'm capable of a certain level of domesticity.
想吃早餐吗
Want some breakfast?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
大姨夫的坏心情仍在继续
And the man period continues unabated.
能送我去学校吗
Can I get a ride to school?
你要我开车送你
You want me to drive you?
有何不可
Yeah, why not?
好
Okay.
不知发生了什么
I wonder what happened.
如果学校停课我会告诉你的
I guess I'll let you know if school gets canceled.
北弗吉尼亚高中
现在的情况太难办了
This is an impossible situation.
哈丽特  要是你没藏那些烟火...
If you hadn't of hidden those fireworks, Harriet...
丹  我为这所学校奉献了一切
I've given this school everything, Dan.
十五年来我一直
For 15 years I've
为这些学生无私奉献
given everything I have to these kids.
他们是我的生命
They're my life.
你知道我不是骗子  你很清楚
And you know I'm not a liar. You know it.
我们先从休假开始
We'll start with a leave of absence.
我们会展开调查
There will be an investigation.
而且哈丽特  我必须告诉你
And, Harriet, I have to tell you
学校是不会支持你的
this school can't stand behind you.
不  不  不
No, no, no!
消防队长让孩子们停课回家了
The fire marshal's sending the kids home.
什么
What?
-有人受伤吗  -没有
- Was anyone hurt? - No.
那就好
Good.
很好
That's good.
我认为我们现在有义务
I think we have an obligation here.
什么义务
What does that mean?
哈丽特会丢掉工作
Harriet's going to lose her job.
还发生了火灾
There was a fire.
可能会有人受伤的
People might have been hurt.
没人受伤
No one was.
可能是卢斯干的  艾米
Could have been Luce. Amy.
他整夜都和我们在家  彼得
He was with us all night, Pete.
-如果你要指控...  -来这套吗
- So if you're accusing... - Really?
不  如果你要指控他
No, if you're accusing him,
先想清楚你到底站在谁那边
just think carefully about who's side you're on.
-老天  -这是我们共同的愿望
- Jesus... - We both wanted this.
不  我的愿望是家庭
No, I wanted a family.
我的愿望简单  理智  正常
I wanted something simple and sane and normal.
我们的生活不非得是政治宣言
Our lives didn't have to be a political fucking statement.
我不想要...
I didn't want...
他
Him?
我认为一定要有
I think there has to be...
某种限度
some kind of limit.
什么限度  告诉我
A limit to what? Tell me.
我爱他的限度吗
To how much I love him?
我努力的限度吗
To how hard I've worked?
为了确保他有机会享受生活  获得成功
To ensure he had a chance at life, at success?
不  彼得  我不同意
No, Pete, I disagree.
这是没有限度的
There is no limit to that,
而学校发生的偶然事故...
and some random accident at school...
-妈的  艾米  -听我说
- Fuck, Amy! - Listen to me!
学校发生的偶然事故不会改变这一点
Some random accident at school is not going to change that.
所以告诉我
So just tell me...
你到底站在谁那边
who's side you're on.
我们这边  艾米
Our side, Amy.
我们这边
Ours.
我的家人这边
My family's.
谢谢你
Thank you.
卢斯  你在哪儿
Luce! Where are you?
我正要离开学校  着火的是威尔逊老师的教室
I'm leaving school. The fire was in Ms. Wilson's classroom.
我觉得过意不去
I feel bad.
我想做点什么安慰她
I want to do something nice for her.
先回家  我来接你
Come home first. I can pick you up.
我马上就回家
I will in just a little.
卢斯  等等
Luce, wait.
爱你
Love you.
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be joking.
德肖恩和我组织全队凑钱买了花
Deshaun and I got the team to chip in for flowers.
德肖恩是吗
Deshaun?
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
我过敏
I'm allergic.
你不能闯进来  卢斯
This is not okay, Luce.
我只是想谈谈
I just want to talk.
这样不行
Well, this is not okay.
太可怕了
That's awful.
有人叫过你黑鬼吗
You ever been called that?
没有
No.
怪不得你总是自视甚高
No wonder you're always so pleased with yourself.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
你气愤人们把你放进盒子里
You're mad people put you in a box.
-是你把我放进盒子里  -我保护了你
- You put me in a box. - I protected you.
但没保护德肖恩
But not Deshaun.
你抓到他之后
After you busted him,
你找来我  科里
you had that meeting with me and Corey
还有队里所有的黑人选手
and all the other black runners on the squad.
你说不沦为刻板印象
And you said it is your solemn duty
是你们庄严的责任
to never be stereotypes.
学学卢斯
Look at Luce.
成为卢斯
Be like Luce.
是的
Yes.
我记得他们都看着我
And I remember them all looking at me.
他们并不嫉妒
They weren't jealous.
他们只是想弄明白
They were just trying to figure it out.
我怎么变成那样
How do I get that?
而我满脑子想的都是德肖恩
And all I can think about was Deshaun.
他唯一的希望就是那个体育奖学金
All he had was that athletic scholarship
而你却把它夺走了
and you took it from him.
你把它夺走是因为他不是我
You took it from him because he wasn't me.
-对  -为什么
- Yes. - Why?
因为多一个我没有打压的德肖恩·米克斯
Because for every Deshaun Meeks I don't come down on,
就会多一个我没法栽培的卢斯·埃德加
there's a Luce Edgar I can't lift out.
胡说八道
That's bullshit.
为什么我们必须做到完美才能被接纳
Why do we have to be perfect to be accepted?
孩子  这就是我们的人生
Boy, that's our life!
不  你只是太渴望得到认可
No, you're so desperate for approval
为此你不惜牺牲自己人
that you'll eat your own just to get it.
-谁的认可  -你觉得呢
- Whose approval? - Who do you think?
每一个让你感到身为黑人不够好的人
Everyone who made you feel like being black wasn't good enough.
但我不需要他们的认可
But I don't need their approval.
我不会为了让别人好受
I'm not going to be somebody's symbol
就化为一个象征
just to make them feel better.
你还是不明白
You still don't get it.
你不明白
You don't get it.
这不仅仅关乎你我
It's not just about you and it's not about me.
美国把你放在盒子里
America put you in a box.
里面狭小肮脏  你动弹不得
And it's tight and it's dirty and you can't move.
但现实就是这样
But guess what? Too bad.
不管你愿不愿意  我们都在一个盒子里
We're all in there together, whether you like it or not.
而盒子里的光是有限的  卢斯
And only so much light gets in that box, Luce.
有人能照到  有人照不到
Some people get it, and some people don't.
但谁能照到不是由你决定的
But it's not on you to decide who gets it and who doesn't.
你说得太对了  是你
You're damn right it's on you!
是你
It's on you.
毕竟  你忙着制造不在场证明的时候
After all, who did you use to do your little errands
你找了谁帮你搞小动作呢
while you were busy establishing alibis?
这不是一回事
It's not the same thing.
你还有很多要学的  小伙子
You got a lot to learn, little man.
现在你给我滚出去
Now you get the fuck out of my house.
滚出去
Get out of my house!
见鬼  见鬼
Shit! Shit!
你在藏圣诞礼物吗
Are you hiding Christmas presents?
你以前就是把我的圣诞礼物藏在那里的
That's where you used to hide my Christmas presents.
你每次都很惊讶
You were always so surprised.
我很擅长表现得惊讶
I'm good at acting surprised.
给你
Here.
还记得丹尼斯吗
Remember Dennis?
记得
Yeah.
我当然记得丹尼斯
Of course I remember Dennis.
我想我们可以再试一次
I thought we could try again.
谢谢
Thanks...
妈妈
Mom.
你的前途一片光明
You have your whole future ahead of you.
充满可能性
Full of potential.
希望你是对的
Hope you're right.
我确定我是对的  亲爱的
I know I'm right, honey.
我确定
I know.
文化月集会
大家好
Hi, everyone.
我想感谢陶森校长给我这个机会
I want thank Principal Towson for giving me this opportunity.
能在此向你们讲述我的故事对我来说意义重大
It means a lot to be able to talk with each of you about my story,
有人说我的故事很独特
which I'm told is pretty unique,
但我还是觉得自己很普通
even though I still feel pretty regular.
我很幸运  有两个了不起的父母
I'm lucky enough to have two amazing parents
他们在我七岁的时候
who when they saw my picture
看到我的照片没有被吓到
at seven years old weren't scared.
或者他们被吓到了  不过掩藏的很好
Or if they were they did a good job of hiding it
因为养育我长大的父母
because the parents I grew up with
心中只有爱和勇气
were nothing but loving and brave.
我来到美国
I came here to America,
来到这所学校
to this school,
然后找到了自我
and I found myself.
第一次见到我母亲的时候
When I first met my mother,
她不会念我的名字
she couldn't pronounce my name.
她一遍又一遍的尝试
She tried over and over
想找准音节的重音
to get the emphasis on the syllables correct,
但她就是不会念
but she just couldn't.
所以我父亲提议给我改名
So my father suggested that they rename me.
他们选了卢斯这个名字  含义是光
They picked Luce, which means light.
因为我妈妈总是说
Because my mom always said that
有一小束光在我体内照耀
there was a little beam of light shone inside me.
要是那束光驱散
If only they could sweep the darkness
前七年的黑暗就好了
of those first seven years away.
我在考虑今晚演讲的内容时
I thought of that as I was figuring out
想到了这件事
what to say to you all tonight.
我意识到身为美国人我是多么幸运
And I realized how lucky I am to be an American.
因为在这里我有重新开始的机会
Because here I got the chance to start over.
在这里我们可以做自己
Here we get to be who we are
虽有缺点仍被接纳
and still be accepted despite our flaws.
在这里我们可以讲述自己的故事
Here we get to tell our own story.
而这是我的故事
This is mine.
他们第一次告诉我我的新名字的时候
When they first told me my new name,
我才刚开始学英语
I was still just learning English,
于是我把它当成了"loose"这个词
so I took it to be the word "loose,"
Loose
L-o-o-s-e,
定义是可拆卸的
which is defined as something detachable,
不易固定的东西
not easily fixed in place, or pinned down...
卢斯